# Vijay Suresh Patil () Featured

(Actively looking)Senior Software Engineer having 5 yr experience in Core Java1.8 concepts like OOP's, multithreading,exception handling,collection. Spring MVC & SpringBoot framework along with Hibernate, restful web services, Mysql, microservices



Current Designation: Sr. Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

Current Company: Tech Mahindra Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree:

Pref. Location: Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: java 8, Core Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Web Services, SOAP, Rest, JPA, J2Ee, Spring

Security, Microservices, Gradle, Log4i, Javascript, JSON, Java, Spring

Mvc, Spring, XML, MySQL, oracle, Linux, Unix, WSDL, Servlets, IOC, ORM, Collections, Multithreading, software developer and the control of the control of

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

## **Summary**

IT professional with 5 years of experience in Development and Maintenance of applications.

Experience in Core Java concept like Oop's, Collection, Multithreading, Exception Handling.

Experience in frameworks like Hibernate 4.X and Spring 4.X, Spring MVC, SpringBoot.

Experience in RestFul webServices.

Extensive experience of working in agile development environment, onsite offshore model and good skills in understanding the Client's business work flow.

## **Work Experience**

**Tech Mahindra** as Sr. Software Engineer

Sep 2019 to Till Date

As a Sr software engineer I am responsible for the development and maintenance of the application.

Cognizant Technology Solutions as Programmer Analyst

May 2018 to Aug 2019

Responsibility: As a Programmer Analyst I am responsible for software development and software maintenance.

Bonellisoft as Software Engineer

Aug 2015 to May 2018

Responsibility: As a Software Engineer I am responsible for software development and software maintenance.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (computer science engineering) from Godavari College Of Engineering in 2015

PG: in 0

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
CORE JAVA		
Hibernate, Spring		
spring boot		
Mysql, Maven		
Html ,Restful web services		
Eclipse		
Apache Tomcat		
WINDOWS		

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Marathi	Expert			

### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

**Employment Status: Full time**